A Finding Aid to the Galerie Chalette Records, 1916-1999, bulk 1939-1994, in the Archives of American Art AAA.galechal
Archives of American Art
- Printed Materials, 1931-1996; Series 4; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 9-10
  - Galerie Chalette Exhibition Catalogs, 1962, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Galerie Chalette Exhibition Invitations, 1958-1964 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - List of Artists' Works (circa 1932-1978), circa 1978 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Museum Information, 1952-circa 1972 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Notes, circa 1980 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Periodicals, 1957-1963 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Periodicals, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Periodicals, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Periodicals, 1966-1971 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Reproduction of Artwork, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Oversized material housed in Box 25, Folder 3.
  - Spanish Lecture, circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Writings, 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Catalog "Derriere Le Miroir: 10 Ans D'Editions", 1956 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Oversized material from Box 9, Folder 10.
  - Reproduction of Artwork, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Oversized material from Box 10, Folder 31.
- Photographs, circa 1920s-1994; Series 5; 7 Linear feet Boxes 10-16, 24-25
  This series contains photographs, slides, negatives, transparencies, and photo albums of artwork, the Lejwa's personal art collection, family photographs, and travel snapshots. Photographs may also be found in Series 2: Artists' Files.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  Subseries 5.1: Art Photographs, circa 1920s-1990s
  Subseries 5.2: Lejwa Personal Photographs, circa 1920s-1994
  - Art Photographs, circa 1920s-1990s; 5.1
    The photographs, transparencies, and slides in this subseries generally consist of professional artwork images, although there are some that include images of artists such as Barbara Hepworth and Jerzy Tchorzewski, and exhibit openings such as Jean Arp and Jan Lebenstein. Also included are 61 black and white prints of Dada artists, taken from 1911-1957, and include artists such as Jean Arp, Hugo Ball, Max Ernst, Emmy Hennings, Kurt Schwitters, and Tristan Tzara. Photographs of the Lejwa's personal collection include professional images as well as personal snapshots. This subseries is arranged alphabetically by last name; photographs of the Lejwa's personal collection, slides and transparencies are filed at the end of this subseries.
    - Jankel Adler, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - G. Alviani, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Jean Arp, undated (Box 10, Folder 10-14)
      Oversized material housed in Box 25, Folder 5.
    - Pierre [Bernard?], undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Kent Bloomer, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Constantin Brancusi, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
      Oversized material housed in Box 25, Folder 4.
    - Georges Braque, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Karol Broniatowski, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Bernard Buffet, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Pierre Caille, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Norman Carlberg, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Marc Chagall, undated (Box 10, Folder 23-24)
    - Chinese Paintings, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Judith Cotton, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - John Cunningham, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Dada Artists, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Deborah de Moulpied, 1960-1967 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Nicolas De Stael, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Edgar Degas, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Robert Delaunay, circa 1933 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Sonia Delaunay, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Andre Derain, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Cesar Domela, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Raoul Dufy, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Robert Engman, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Max Ernst, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Wojciech Fangor, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Otto Freundlich, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Sue Fuller, circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Pablo Gargallo, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Stefan Gierowski, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Thomas Gleb, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Julio Gonzalez, undated (Box 11, Folder 15-17)
    - Juan Gris, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Vera Haller, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Erwin Hauer, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Barbara Hepworth, undated (Box 11, Folder 21-22)
    - Auguste Herbin, undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Hannah Höch, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Francois Hugo, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Josef Israels, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Johannes Itten, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Robert Jacobson, undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Paul Kallos, undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Vassily Kandinsky, undated (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Lajos Kassak, undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Paul Katz, undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Keineny, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Ellsworth Kelly, undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Bronislaw Kierzkowski, undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Henri Laurens, undated (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Jan Lebenstien, undated (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Jan Lebenstien, undated (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
    - Fernand Leger, undated (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
    - Jacques Lipchitz, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Alberto Magnelli, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Aristide Maillol, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Kazinir Malevitch, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Alfred Manessier, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Manolo, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Giacomo Manzo, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Marino Marini, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Umberto Mastroianni, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Henri Matisse, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Zygmond Meinkes, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Jean Metzinger, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Joan Miro, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Amedeo Modigliani, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Laszlo Moholy-Nagy, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Henry Moore, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Pablo Picasso, undated (Box 12, Folder 22-25)
    - Jackson Pollock, undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - William Reimann, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - August Rodin, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Ronalt, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Rugs by Painters, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Ilja Schor, undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Kurt Schwitters, undated (Box 12, Folder 32-33)
    - Sculpture by Painters, undated (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Stephanie Scuris, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Gustave Singier, undated (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Henryk Stazewski, undated (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Jonasz Stern, undated (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Wladyslaw Strzeminski, undated (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Sophie Taeuber-Arp, undated (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Jerzy Tchorzewski, undated (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Walasse Ting, undated (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Joaquin Torres-Garcia, undated (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Igael Tumarkin, undated (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Georges Valmier, undated (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Victor Vasarely, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Mary Vieira, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Max Weber, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Fritz Wortruba, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Yale Group, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Robert Zeidman, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Lejwa Personal Collection (Box 13)
      - Jean Arp, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Georges Braque, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Michel Cadoret, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Marc Chagall, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Cycladic Sculpture, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Sonia Delaunay, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Andre Derain, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - Burgoyne Diller, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - Marcel Duchamp, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - Raymond Duchamp-Villon, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - Max Ernst, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - Wojciech Fangor, undated (Box 13, Folder 18-19)
      - Julio Gonzalez, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
      - Robert Gonzalez, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
      - Henri Laurens, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
      - Fernand Leger, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
      - Henri Matisse, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Joan Miro, undated (Box 13, Folder 25)
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 13, Folder 26-27)
      - Negatives, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 13, Folder 28-29)
      - Pablo Picasso, undated (Box 13, Folder 30)
      - Polish Menorah (17th century), 1973 (Box 13, Folder 31)
      - Pottery, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 13, Folder 32)
      - Hans Richter (Marcel Duchamp with rotorelief), circa 1947 (Box 13, Folder 33)
      - Michel Seuphor, undated (Box 13, Folder 34)
      - Henryk Stazewski, undated (Box 13, Folder 35)
      - Henri Toulouse-Lautrec, undated (Box 13, Folder 36)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 13, Folder 37)
      - Victor Vasarely, undated (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Slides, undated (Box 13, Folder 39-41)
    - Transparencies, undated (Box 13, Folder 42-44)
    - Slide Boxes (Box 24)
      - Arp, Roy Friedman, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Dada Color Slides, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Burgoyne Diller, undated (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
      - Wojciech Fangor, undated (Box 24, Folder 5-8)
      - Wojciech Fangor Exhibition, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 9-10)
      - Gallery shots, undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Gonzalez, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - Hilla Rebay, undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - Jan Lebenstein, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - Pablo Picasso, undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Smith and Fleishman, undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Photograph, "Portrait of Brancusi", undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Oversized material from Box 10, Folder 17.
    - Photographs of Arp bronze sculpture, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Oversized material from Box 10, Folders 10-14.
  - Lejwa Personal Photographs, circa 1920s-1994; 5.2
    This subseries contains snapshots, negatives, and slides of artwork, family, friends, and Madeleine Lejwa's travels in the 1980s and 1990s. Eight photo albums include six albums of photos from Madeleine Lejwa's travels in the late 1970s-early 1990s, one album of photos of china and silverware, and an album of photos of the townhouse at 9 East 88th Street. This subseries is arranged alphabetically by subject, then by last name or subject. Photographs and negatives are filed together; however, slides and photo albums are separated and located at the end of the subseries. This subseries is from the 2005 collection addition and is minimally processed.
    - 9 East 88th Street, 1991, undated (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Artwork (Box 13)
      - Jean Arp, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 46)
      - Jean Arp Dedication at New York University, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 47)
      - Jean Arp Installation in Jerusalem, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 48)
      - Max Bill in Jerusalem, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 49)
      - Rickey in Jerusalem, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 50)
      - Unidentified, 1922 (Box 13, Folder 51)
      - Unidentified, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 13, Folder 52)
    - Family (Box 14)
      - Chalette Family, circa 1938-1957 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Leon Chalette, 1932-1958 (Box 14, Folder 2)
        Oversized material housed in Box 25, Folder 6.
      - Leon Chalette and Madeleine Chalette Lejwa, 1928-1940 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Leon Chalette and Madeleine Chalette Lejwa, Shanghai, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Arthur Lejwa, 1939-1971 (Box 14, Folder 5)
        Oversized material housed in Box 25, Folders 7-8.
      - Arthur Lejwa and Madeleine Chalette Lejwa, 1939-1968 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Madeleine Chalette Lejwa, 1945-1994 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Madeleine Chalette Lejwa, Oppenheim Collins, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Madeleine Chalette Lejwa, Portraits, 1931-1965 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Galerie Chalette, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Guggenheim Museum, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Jewelry, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Parties, 1968, 1985-1991 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - People (Box 14)
      - Jean and Marguerite Arp, 1968-circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - Colleagues and Friends, circa 1920s-1991 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Kenan Erim (Aphrodisias), 1984-1989 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - Robert Gould Research Foundation Scientific Advisory Committee, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Robert Gould Research Foundation, Site Preparation, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Unidentified, circa 1920s-1990s (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Press Photos (Box 14)
      - Chinese Cities, 1931-1945 (Box 14, Folder 21)
      - Hong Kong, 1929-1949 (Box 14, Folder 22)
      - Shanghai, 1932-1949 (Box 14, Folder 23)
      - Tibet, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 24)
      - Tokyo and Japan, circa 1928-1955 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Travel (Box 14)
      - Aboard the Argonaut, 1982, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 26)
      - Aphrodisias (Turkey), 1984 (Box 14, Folder 27)
      - Australia, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 28)
      - China and Hong Kong, circa 1980s (Box 14, Folder 29-30)
      - Egypt, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 31)
      - Europe, 1967, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 14, Folder 32)
      - Germany, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 33)
      - Greece, circa 1982 (Box 14, Folder 34)
      - Israel, 1972, circa 1980s (Box 14, Folder 35)
      - Israel, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 36)
      - Italy, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Travel (Box 15)
      - Italy, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Italy, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Italy, undated (Box 15, Folder 3-5)
      - Japan, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
      - Jordan, circa 1981 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous Negatives, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous Photographs, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - MTS Argonaut, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Museums, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Russia, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Sachsenhausen (Germany), 1994 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Spain, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Turkey, 1984-1992 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Venice Bienale, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - Venice Bienale, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Slides, circa 1980s (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Photo Albums (Box 16)
      - 9 East 88th Street, circa 1980s (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Aphrodisias Album in Honor of Kenan Erim, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Australia, Colombia, Solduno with Marguerite Arp, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Max Bill Dedication in Jerusalem, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Egypt and Jordan, circa 1970s (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Greece with the Met, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Sachsenhausen, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Silver and Chinaware, circa 1960s (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Slide Boxes (Box 24)
      - Bogota, Colombia, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - Colombia, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - New Year's Eve, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 19-20)
      - Travels, 1982-circa 1990s (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - Unlabeled, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Photograph of Leon Chalette, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
      Oversized material from Box 14, Folder 2.
    - Photographs of Arthur Lejwa, undated (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
      Oversized material from Box 14, Folder 5.
- Legal Records, 1938, 1959-1988; Series 6; 0.8 Linear feet Box 17
  This series contains records pertaining to litigation against Galerie Chalette. The Lebenstein v. Lejwa (31325.002) folder titles were taken from the original folders; the numerical notation refers to the law firm's client number. Personal legal records can be found in Series 7: Personal Papers.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by case name and then type of material.
  - Diller v. Lejwa, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - Diller v. Lejwa, Exhibition Catalogs, Court Exhibits, 1961-1988 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Diller v. Lejwa, Photographs of Diller's Artwork, 1938-1964 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Lebenstein v. Lejwa, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Lebenstein v. Lejwa, Correspondence, circa 1960s-1974 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Lebenstein v. Lejwa, Court Record, circa 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Lebenstein v. Lejwa (31325.002) (Box 17)
    - Bank Statements, 1962-1964 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Bills, 1961-1963 (Box 17, Folder 9-10)
    - Catalogues, 1961-1972 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Client's Papers, 1965-1968 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Court Record, 1965-1974 (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
    - Gimpel Fils, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Hold, circa 1965 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Memos of Fact, 1965-1973 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Original Documents, 1960-1962 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Printed Materials, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Promotional Efforts, 1961-1963 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Working Papers, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 22)
- Personal Papers of Arthur and Madeleine Chalette Lejwa, 1925-1999; Series 7; 3.7 Linear feet Boxes 17-21, 25
  This series includes biographical information, personal correspondence, business and legal records, and printed materials. This series is created from the 2005 collection addition and is minimally processed.
  The series is arranged as 5 subseries:
  Subseries 7.1: Biographical Files, 1925-1996
  Subseries 7.2: Personal Correspondence, 1939-1996
  Subseries 7.3: Business Records, 1968-1995
  Subseries 7.4: Legal Records, 1940-1996
  Subseries 7.5: Printed Materials, 1929-1999
  - Biographical Files, 1925-1996; 7.1
    This subseries includes personal documents, such as immigration documents, passports, and the Lejwa's marriage license. It is arranged alphabetically by last name, then type of material.
    - Leon Chalette, circa 1946 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Arthur Lejwa (Box 17)
      - Curriculum Vitae, 1939-1951 (Box 17, Folder 24-25)
      - Death Certificate, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Passport, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 27)
      - Professional Documentation, 1925-1961 (Box 17, Folder 28)
        Oversized diploma housed in Box 25, Folder 9.
    - Madeleine Lejwa (Box 17)
      - Business Cards, undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - Certificate of Naturalization, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 30)
      - Passports, 1977-1987 (Box 17, Folder 31)
      - Voting Records, 1948, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Lejwa Catalogue, circa 1996 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Lejwa Marriage, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Diploma of Arthur Lejwa, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      Oversized material from Box 17, Folder 28.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1939-1996; 7.2
    The bulk of the personal correspondence is to Arthur Lejwa and is either from friends and colleagues, or related to Lejwa's work as a biochemist in the 1940s. A significant amount of Arthur Lejwa's correspondence is in Polish, Yiddish, and German. There is also correspondence regarding donations to institutions in Israel. More personal correspondence may also be found in Series 1: Correspondence and Subseries 7.3: Business Records. This subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent or type of material.
    - Appraisals, 1968-1981 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Max Bill, 1979-1982 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Leon Chalette, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - The Israel Museum, 1967-1975 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - The Jerusalem Foundation, Arp, 1971-1976 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - The Jerusalem Foundation, General, 1970-1995 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - The Jerusalem Foundation, Michel Levin, 1970-1984 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - The Jerusalem Foundation, Rickey, 1971-1973 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Teddy Kollek, 1967-1979 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Letters from Arthur and Madeleine Lejwa, 1951, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Letters to Arthur Lejwa, 1939-1954 (Box 18, Folder 11-22)
    - Letters to Madeleine Chalette Lejwa, 1961-1996 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Letters to Madeleine Chalette Lejwa, 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 24-25)
    - Pan American Medical Association, 1944-1954 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Robert Gould Research Foundation, 1940-1948 (Box 18, Folder 27-28)
    - Jeremy Shamos, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Business Records, 1968-1995; 7.3
    This subseries contains records of the Lejwa's personal donations and purchases. Additional business records may be found in Series 3: General Business Files. It is arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Donations to The Jerusalem Foundation, Scholarships, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Donations to The Jerusalem Foundation, Sculptures, 1970-1995 (Box 18, Folder 31-32)
    - Jewelry, 1969-1987 (Box 18, Folder 33-34)
    - Memberships, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Personal Art Purchases, 1969-1980 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Receipts, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Legal Records, 1940-1996; 7.4
    The bulk of the legal records in this subseries are related to settling Arthur Lejwa's estate after his death in 1972 and Madeleine Lejwa's will. Additional legal records may be found in Series 6: Legal Records. This subseries is arranged alphabetically by type of material, then chronologically.
    - 9 East 88th Street, NY, 1963, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Agreement between Madeleine Lejwa and American Friends of Hebrew University, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 39-40)
    - Agreement for Migration from Poland, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Art Collection Inventory, 1975-1986 (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Burial Plots in Jerusalem, 1972-1974 (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - Duell v. Lejwa and Ducovny, 1949-1959 (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - Estate of Arthur Lejwa (Box 18)
      - Mary Behme (Accountant), 1973-1978 (Box 18, Folder 45)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1977 (Box 18, Folder 46)
      - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 18, Folder 47)
      - Correspondence, 1973-1979 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Estate Tax Audit, 1973-1975 (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
      - Federal Estate Tax Return, 1972-1976 (Box 19, Folder 5-8)
      - Federal and New York State Estate Tax Filing, 1973-1985 (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
      - Fiduciary Income Tax Returns, 1972-1978 (Box 19, Folder 11-12)
      - Galerie Chalette, 1953-1972 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - General, 1972-1980 (Box 19, Folder 14-16)
      - Income Tax Liability, 1970-1980 (Box 19, Folder 17-18)
      - Income Tax Returns, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - IRS Adjustments, 1973-1978 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - IRS Valuation of Art, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Legal Research, 1972-1977 (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - New York Estate Taxes, 1973-1975 (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - New York State Tax Payment, 1973-1976 (Box 19, Folder 24)
      - Pictures Not Used, circa 1972-1974 (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - Sales Tax Audit, 1972-1974 (Box 19, Folder 26)
      - Sotheby Parke-Bernet Appraisal, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 27)
      - Trubin Sillcocks Edelman and Knapp, 1974-1978 (Box 19, Folder 28)
      - Waiver of Statute of Limitations, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Estate of Madeleine Lejwa, Paid Bills, 1996-1999 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Estate of Madeleine Lejwa, Sotheby's Appraisal, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 31-33)
    - Arthur Lejwa, Power of Attorney, 1951, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Arthur Lejwa, Will, 1959, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Madeleine Lejwa, Living Will, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Madeleine Lejwa, Will, 1976-1996 (Box 19, Folder 37-39)
    - Madeleine Lejwa, Will, 1976-1996 (Box 20, Folder 1-4)
    - New York University Madeleine Lejwa Fund - Aphrodisias, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Printed Materials, 1929-1999; 7.5
    This subseries contains newspaper clippings, publications, reports, notebooks and writings. Much of the material is related to Arthur Lejwa's professional career prior to and at the Robert Gould Research Foundation. It includes copies of Arthur Lejwa's publications and his scientific notebooks. This series also contains materials related to institutions in which the Lejwa's donated. Many of the newspaper clippings are very brittle and in Hebrew. This subseries is arranged alphabetically by type of material.